Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
My name is Georgiana Saffa, born in Sierra Leone, settled down in UK.
I'm 55 years old.
I have been living in the UK for 25 years.
All my life in the UK had been full of sickness.
I never had any quality time in the UK.
I started to work, settled down and bought houses.
I have about three houses in London through the job I was doing – a very good job -
helping women in the community who were trying to settle down in the country,
trying to go to college, start their own business or get a job.
That was the job I was doing – very demanding – running around for them.
At one stage, they even called my house, Social Services house
because as soon as somebody arrived, the first person they would call was me.
... accommodation problem, everything.
The job was going very well for me in London.
My life was very good; I was driving a very good, brand new car.
In London, we drive by registration; every year, the car that comes out -
you'll drive it and people will think you have money.
I didn't have any problems.
At one stage, the government gave me a car to drive.
I was very popular in London.
I got a job in the MP's office.
I became a campaign manager for the whole of Westminster – North.
I was employed in this office which is part of the Labour Party.
Whenever elections came up, I was one of the permanent staff that participated in the process.
I went to the polling station, amongst other things.
This is me on the picture with the MP - Karen Buck, in Westminster City Council.
It is the office I used to work in.
She was my very close friend.
This is our president.
When he came to London, they told him that I was helping a lot of Sierra Leoneans that were refugees.
I was the one helping them around and the president was happy about it.
That's my last son - this is the one they took from me when I was in the hospital.
Now, he is 17 years old.
These are my two daughters - about three weeks ago they visited me in Ghana for the first time.
Everything was going very well for me.
Then, I started to have chronic headaches.
I told my younger sister who is a nurse about my headache and inability to sleep.
She replied that it was alarming and that I should go to my doctor for a brain scan.
At that time, I was still working but my behaviour in the office was so bad
that they set up a camera to monitor me in the office, without my knowledge.
So all along, while I was fighting my colleagues, they were recording it.
One day, the manager rang me and told me that he wanted to see me in the office, that there was a problem.
I said, "OK, I will come".
When I got there, they played back the recordings of all my aggressive misbehaviours.
Even the way I spoke to customers on the phone was all recorded.
They told me that my situation was very severe and so they could no longer employ me.
They told me to go and seek for help.
Immediately I told my sister, she said I should see my doctor.
I was sent for an MRI scan.
The first scan that was done, I was told that the nerves between my brain cells were becoming swollen.
That was why I was getting blood clots on my eyes.
I couldn’t sleep properly.
All these problems were arising.
I was put on medication.
Initially, it was one but I ended up on 14 different types of medication.
Some of them were for my mood and some caused me kidney problems.
But I thank God for Jesus that it has gone.
My problems are gone.
I thank God.
These documents were from my GP in London stating the medication I was on.
I had medication for mood, sleep, asthma and gas.
I had bleeding because of too much medication in my system.
All that caused me headaches.
I was going through a lot of problems.
These problems became a big agony for me such that my children had to be taken away from me immediately.
I was not happy having my children taken away from me but they were little and didn't have a choice,
unless you are 16 years of age.
Babies can be taken away.
My children were put into foster care.
Seeing my children was a problem for me.
It took a while for me to come to myself.
They started to monitor me with my children.
Video cameras would be on me to see the way I behaved with them.
After one or two hours, I would be told that the meeting with my children was over.
At that time, I would get pregnant by different types of men who would take advantage of me.
I had about eight abortions and seven children by different fathers.
Some of them didn’t even know their fathers.
They would ask me where their dad was and I would reply that I didn't know -
at that time, I was on drugs and very sick.
You mean to say, madam - because of this problem, you had seven children with six different men?
Yes.
And majority of your children don't know who their father is?
Of course, yes.
Even now, I don't know what to tell them.
All this led me being neglected, even by my family, 15 of whom I brought to London.
None of them came to help me.
I was very neglected.
Nobody cared about my health.
They were even laughing at me, stating that I was a mad woman – mentally ill, that I was finished.
Because of this sickness, I gave my life to Christ.
I was born as a Muslim.
OK. Sorry, before going ahead, madam - you mentioned that because the situation became so serious,
the government actually had to take your children from you.
What was your behaviour at home that caused the government to come and
take all of your seven children away from you, to put them into foster care?
I couldn’t look after myself or my children.
They were neglected – going to school dirty.
Sometimes, they would not even go to school.
In the morning, I would just close my door and say, "Today, no school!"
The school rang social services to inform them that my children were not coming to school.
Social services intervened, came to my house and took my children away from me.
Ms Georgiana Saffa
Morning Water Testimony
At that time, I wanted to commit suicide.
I was living on the third floor but they put me on the ground floor because of my suicide attempts.
OK, you said you attempted suicide.
How did you actually try to go about this, because of this mental disorder you were having at this time?
I attempted suicide about five or six times.
When they got to know, they put me on the ground floor and put me on Suicide Watch.
Even when I was in the toilet and bathroom, in my house, somebody had to be with me all the time -
watching me, taking record of how I was behaving and what was happening in my life.
When you were on the third floor - was it that you attempted to jump?
Yes, I attempted to jump about five times.
One of my daughters saw me doing it and told the police that her mum wanted to commit suicide.
I think we can all understand the severity of our sister's problem,
to the extent that she had to be monitored 24/7.
She was placed under Suicide Watch.
Someone had to be with her all the time because of the severity of her mental condition,
that actually pushed her to attempt suicide on numerous occasions.
Just before that you said that this actually led many different men to use and abuse you.
What do you mean by that?
How would you meet such men and how would they take advantage of you, in your mental problem?
I am a very popular woman in London.
I had male friends but had no relationship with them.
When they knew I was sick and not all that strong, some of them would come to me as friends,
stating that only they understood my problem, that I shouldn't worry as they would be with me
but as time went on, when I would tell them I was pregnant by them, they would just disappear.
With the pregnancies, the government said that as I could not look after myself,
I couldn't look after my children.
So, some of the children were taken from me while I was in hospital.
The day I would get pregnant, they would monitor me, take me to hospital and do everything for me.
The day of my delivery, I wouldn’t even go through labour; they would do a caesarean
because they didn’t want me to go through labour in case I killed the child.
They would just operate on me, take the baby and immediately,
the foster parents would be there to collect the baby from me.
I didn't breastfeed at all.
The moment you gave birth to these children, they were taken away by the government immediately?
Immediately, they had to go.
Some of them, I wouldn’t see for 10 or 15 years.
Some of them 22 years.
It is now they are coming into my life by the grace in the life of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Thank You, Jesus!
Once again, we are just asking this question for everyone to understand the severity of the situation.
Before our sister came to The SCOAN by the grace of God, she had given birth to so many children
but she was not even able to stay with them as a mother because of her mental condition,
even to the point that some of her last children, as she gave birth to them,
right there and then in the hospital, they were taken away and put into foster care.
They were brought up without even knowing their mother because of the severity of her condition.
So madam, you said that you had tried so many different means to get solution to this problem,
before you came to The SCOAN.
Can you just mention again some of the diverse places you went to, trying to get rid of this problem?
The first time I entered church - I have a friend, she is from Uganda – she came to my house
and told me that I was a very nice person but that I needed to follow her to church.
This lady ran after me for over six months.
One day, my mum was with me and told me to follow my friend to the church, that Jesus could heal me.
Immediately, I got up, changed my clothes and followed the lady to the church.
When she took me to church, I gave my life to Christ.
I started going to different churches, sleeping in the church, even on the floor.
I would lie down in the church.
People would laugh at me, jeering, "You haven't seen nothing yet. This is not going to go away".
I travelled to Mali, Senegal and Gambia to do different sacrifices.
People who knew me would contribute money and tell me to go to different places to seek healing.
You said that when you went to these countries, you did sacrifices.
What do you mean by that?
Can you explain what happened when you went there?
When I got for the sacrifices, they would tell me that the devil could do this and that.
They would tell me to buy a big cow, pray on it and my sickness would go away.
I even have some of the pictures of that.
My sickness would subdue but when I would return, it would get worse
and they would have to hospitalise me, straight into the mental hospital.
I would not receive any solution at all.
So, you were a regular customer at the psychiatric hospitals in London because of this condition?
Yes.
OK.
Now, in the midst of all of this, you said earlier that by the special grace of God you went to Ghana,
where you were introduced to The SCOAN.
Repeat for us, madam - what happened when you had the opportunity to come here to The SCOAN
and receive the Morning Water.
When I came here with my friend, I was privileged to get the Morning Water
which my friend encouraged me to use.
I told her I had been using too many things.
She told me that this was my last bus stop.
I replied, "In the name of Jesus!"
I started taking it instead of the tablets.
The first day the Morning Water was ministered to me in The SCOAN, Ghana branch,
I went home and slept like a baby.
I slept so much that they had to wake me up to take breakfast.
I complained that I hadn’t slept for a long time, that they should let me sleep.
So before this time, how was your sleep like?
I was on two different types of sleeping tablets.
You must know how severe my situation was.
Not only one tablet; one is 48 mg, I have them with me, the other one is about 36 mg.
I had to take both tablets together to sleep but even with that, the sleep would not come.
I even overdosed myself at one stage.
I ended up in hospital.
I was put on a drip to flush all the medication that was in my system.
I nearly killed myself that time.
Our sister was actually dependant, addicted to taking tablets to be able to sleep.
After you received the Morning Water, that night you were able to sleep peacefully
for the first time in many years?
All my life.
I slept, I said that this one was very serious.
Thank You, Jesus!
As I was going back to London, I got the Morning Water and went with it.
While I was in London, I was ministering it throughout.
I refused to take my medication which raised an alarm among the doctors.
But luckily, the type of doctors that I had, they were very understanding; they were Christians.
They said that they understood that God could heal.
They asked me where I went and I told my GP that I was in The SCOAN in Nigeria.
He said, "You have done well; I am happy for you".
Ms Georgiana Saffa
Morning Water Testimony
That's not enough.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
This is a situation truly beyond the power of nature.
We don't try, in any way, to suggest that the medical doctors cannot help or assist people in this situation,
but it is clear for all to hear that our sister's case was beyond the power of human comprehension,
it was beyond the power of nature, it required divine intervention.
That is how after receiving the Morning Water, our sister stopped taking all the medications
she was dependant on, for so many years.
We can just see... what is it that you are holding there, madam?
These are some of the medications.
I didn’t want to see them anymore; so, I took them out of the packet and threw them away.
I just have the empty packets with me now because I don’t want to see them anymore.
They are my enemies.
Ms Georgiana Saffa
Morning Water Testimony
Our sister is holding just few examples of the many different types of tablets she was taking to try
to relieve her situation - a very severe case of mental problem coupled with severe headaches,
alongside different other medical problems: hypertension, very severe eye problem.
So many different health complications that really crippled our sister's life.
She was doing very well in the UK in a prominent job.
Everything went downhill, after very severe migraine headaches struck.
But we give glory to God that she has been restored by our Lord, Jesus Christ.
Madam, as you are standing here right now to the glory of God, how is your health condition right now?
My health is perfect.
I have even lost weight as I am not taking the tablets anymore.
I was almost a size 22; now, I am size 16.
I am a brand new woman, in the name of Jesus Christ of Nazareth and the God of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Thank You, Jesus!
That very severe headache that initially started with all these mental problems - do you mean it is gone?
It's gone.
I don’t experience any problems, not even sleeping problems; now, I sleep like a baby.
I can fall asleep even while sitting.
Now, I even take coffee so as not to sleep!
Can you believe that?
Wow, thank You, Jesus Christ!
Let's put our hands together one more time for Jesus Christ!
Finally madam, you said that right now, after Jesus Christ has restored your health, to the glory of God,
you have begun to reconcile with some of your children, that actually you had never seen,
right since birth, because of the severity of your problem.
You mean that by now, by the grace of God, you have been able to reconcile and meet with some of them?
Yes, three of my children came to visit me; they were in Ghana three weeks ago.
They came to visit me for the first time.
When they came, they were shocked and said, "Mummy, you have changed! You behave like a small girl."
I told them that I am a brand new woman now.
Everything has changed in my life.
They were surprised that I was behaving like a small girl.
Previously, we would fight and they would abandon me and go and stay in a hotel.
But now, we sleep, eat, go out and do everything together.
I went shopping with them.
I will follow them to the airport whereas before, I would say, "I am not going; I'm not feeling good".
But now, they are very happy.
I took them to The SCOAN branch in Ghana.
At the moment, they watch on Youtube.
They are very happy and have asked me to bring the Morning Water for them.
Hallelujah! This is indeed a radical transformation.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Wow, thank You, Jesus Christ!
We give all the glory to God.
There are no natural words to describe what Jesus Christ has done in the life of our sister, except to say,
"Thank You, Jesus".
Finally, madam, this Morning Water that you are holding right now - what is your advice to the world,
and your encouragement to the world concerning the wonderful blessing of God
that you are holding right now, that God used as an instrument to restore your sanity, health,
after so many years wandering in such a terrible problem?
This Morning Water is so wonderful that I can't even go without it.
Don’t joke with it, no matter what type of situation you are going through, what type of sickness,
or problem you are facing.
Find the solution.
Morning Water is the best - it can solve...
If it can solve my problem – so big that even the British government knew about it,
it can solve anybody's problem.
There is no distance for Jesus.
Jesus is everywhere in this world.
The Morning Water – minister it very well and have confidence in it.
My brothers and sisters - it will never let you down, in the name of Jesus Christ of Nazareth
and the God of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Amen! One more time, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
RV: Mel Flowers 18/03/2019